现在我们将讨论3D中旋转的一个更令人困惑的元素。
Now we're going to talk about one of the more perplexing elements of rotations in 3D.
我这里有三个坐标框架，它们最初都是相互平行的。
I've got three coordinate frames here and they're all initially parallel to each other.
x轴，y轴和z轴都是对齐的。
The x-axes, the y-axes and the z-axes are all aligned.
我要拿起第一个，红色的那个，我要将它旋转+90度
I'm going to pick up the first one, the red one, and I'm going to rotate it by +90 degrees
围绕它的x轴。
around its x-axis.
正向是这个方向，所以在x轴上旋转90度后，它看起来像
Positive is in this direction so after rotating it by 90 degrees in x-axis, it looks like
这个。
this.
而现在我要围绕y轴旋转+90度。
And now I'm going to rotate it by +90 degrees around the y-axis.
所以这个框架最终看起来像这样。
So this frame is going to end up looking like this.
这是它的最终定位。
This is its final orientation.
我只想把它放在那里。
I'm just going to put it down there.
我打算拿起蓝框，我将在相反的位置进行旋转
I'm going to pick up the blue frame and I'm going to do the rotation within the opposite
订购。
order.
首先，我要围绕y轴旋转+90度。
First of all, I'm going to rotate it by +90 degrees around the y-axis.
这是积极的方向。
That's the positive direction.
所以它最初看起来像这样。
So it's initially going to look like this.
现在我要围绕x轴旋转+90度。
And now I'm going to rotate it by +90 degrees around the x-axis.
x轴现在指向下方，这是正旋转方向。
The x-axis is now pointing downwards, that's the positive rotation direction.
所以这就是最终定位的样子。
So this is what the final orientation will look like.
我们可以看到这两个框架的方向非常不同。
And we can see that these two frames have gotten very, very different orientations.
因此，当涉及到三维旋转时，您执行它们的顺序
So when it comes to doing rotations in three dimensions, the order in which you do them
至关重要。
is critically important.
轮换不是可交换的。
Rotations are not to commutative.
让我们看一下旋转矩阵乘法的非交换性质。
Let's look at the non-commutative nature of rotation matrix multiplication.
我将围绕x轴旋转90度。
I'm going to have a rotation of 90 degrees around the x-axis.
然后我将围绕y轴旋转90度。
And then I'm going to rotate by 90 degrees around the y-axis.
结果旋转矩阵看起来像这样。
And the resulting rotation matrix looks like this.
如果我以相反的顺序执行此操作，我将首先围绕y轴旋转，然后我将旋转
If I do this in the opposite order, I'll rotate around the y-axis first, and then I'll rotate
在x轴周围，每种情况下都是90度。
around the x-axis, by 90 degrees in each case.
我最终得到了一个看起来像这样的旋转矩阵。
I end up with a resulting rotation matrix which looks like this.
我们可以看到这两个矩阵是完全不同的。
And we can see that these two matrices are quite different.
当您将旋转矩阵相乘时，顺序非常重要。
When you're multiplying rotation matrices, the order is critically important.